The President: Good evening.
On Wednesday, 14 Americans
were killed as they came
together to celebrate
the holidays.
They were taken from family
and friends
who loved them deeply.
They were white and
black; Latino and Asian;
immigrants and
American-born;
moms and dads;
daughters and sons.
Each of them served their
fellow citizens and all of
them were part of
our American family.
Tonight, I want to talk
with you about this tragedy,
the broader threat
of terrorism,
and how we can keep
our country safe.
The FBI is still gathering
the facts about what
happened in San Bernardino,
but here is what we know.
The victims were brutally
murdered and injured by one
of their coworkers
and his wife.
So far, we have no evidence
that the killers were
directed by a terrorist
organization overseas,
or that they were part of a
broader conspiracy here at home.
But it is clear that the two
of them had gone down the
dark path of radicalization,
embracing a perverted
interpretation of Islam
that calls for war
against America and the West.
They had stockpiled assault
weapons, ammunition,
and pipe bombs.
So this was an
act of terrorism,
designed to kill
innocent people.
Our nation has been at war
with terrorists since al
Qaeda killed nearly
3,000 Americans on 9/11.
In the process, we've
hardened our defenses --
from airports to
financial centers,
to other critical
infrastructure.
Intelligence and law
enforcement agencies have
disrupted countless
plots here and overseas,
and worked around the
clock to keep us safe.
Our military and
counterterrorism
professionals have
relentlessly pursued
terrorist networks overseas
-- disrupting safe havens in
several different countries,
killing Osama bin Laden,
and decimating al
Qaeda's leadership.
Over the last few
years, however,
the terrorist threat has
evolved into a new phase.
As we've become better
at preventing complex,
multifaceted
attacks like 9/11,
terrorists turned to less
complicated acts of violence
like the mass shootings that
are all too common
in our society.
It is this type of attack
that we saw at Fort Hood in
2009; in Chattanooga
earlier this year;
and now in San Bernardino.
And as groups like ISIL grew
stronger amidst the chaos of
war in Iraq and then Syria,
and as the Internet erases
the distance
between countries,
we see growing efforts by
terrorists to poison the
minds of people like the
Boston Marathon bombers and
the San Bernardino killers.
For seven years, I've
confronted this evolving
threat each morning in
my intelligence briefing.
And since the day
I took this office,
I've authorized U.S. forces
to take out
terrorists abroad precisely
because I know how
real the danger is.
As Commander-in-Chief,
I have no greater
responsibility than the
security of the American people.
As a father to two young
daughters who are the most
precious part of my life, I
know that we see ourselves
with friends and coworkers
at a holiday party like the
one in San Bernardino.
I know we see our kids
in the faces of the young
people killed in Paris.
And I know that
after so much war,
many Americans are asking
whether we are confronted by
a cancer that has
no immediate cure.
Well, here's what I want
you to know: The threat from
terrorism is real, but
we will overcome it.
We will destroy ISIL and
any other organization
that tries to harm us.
Our success won't
depend on tough talk,
or abandoning our values,
or giving into fear.
That's what groups like
ISIL are hoping for.
Instead, we will prevail
by being strong and smart,
resilient and relentless,
and by drawing upon every
aspect of American power.
Here's how.
First, our military will
continue to hunt down
terrorist plotters in
any country
where it is necessary.
In Iraq and Syria,
airstrikes are taking out
ISIL leaders, heavy weapons,
oil tankers, infrastructure.
And since the
attacks in Paris,
our closest allies --
including France, Germany,
and the United Kingdom
-- have ramped up their
contributions to our
military campaign,
which will help us
accelerate our effort
to destroy ISIL.
Second, we will continue
to provide training and
equipment to tens of
thousands of Iraqi and
Syrian forces fighting ISIL
on the ground so that we
take away their safe havens.
In both countries, we're
deploying Special Operations
Forces who can accelerate
that offensive.
We've stepped up this effort
since the attacks in Paris,
and we'll continue to invest
more in approaches that are
working on the ground.
Third, we're working with
friends and allies to stop
ISIL's operations
-- to disrupt plots,
cut off their financing, and
prevent them from recruiting
more fighters.
Since the attacks in
Paris, we've surged
intelligence-sharing
with our European allies.
We're working with Turkey to
seal its border with Syria.
And we are cooperating with
Muslim-majority countries --
and with our Muslim
communities here at home --
to counter the vicious
ideology that ISIL
promotes online.
Fourth, with
American leadership,
the international community
has begun to establish a
process -- and timeline --
to pursue ceasefires and a
political resolution
to the Syrian war.
Doing so will allow the
Syrian people and every
country, including
our allies,
but also countries
like Russia,
to focus on the common goal
of destroying ISIL -- a
group that threatens us all.
This is our strategy
to destroy ISIL.
It is designed and supported
by our military commanders
and counterterrorism
experts,
together with 65 countries
that have joined an
American-led coalition.
And we constantly examine
our strategy to determine
when additional steps are
needed to get the job done.
That's why I've ordered the
Departments of State and
Homeland Security to review
the visa *Waiver program
under which the female
terrorist in San Bernardino
originally came
to this country.
And that's why I will
urge high-tech and law
enforcement leaders to make
it harder for terrorists to
use technology to
escape from justice.
Now, here at home, we have
to work together to address
the challenge.
There are several steps that
Congress should
take right away.
To begin with, Congress
should act to make sure no
one on a no-fly list
is able to buy a gun.
What could possibly be the
argument for allowing a
terrorist suspect to buy
a semi-automatic weapon?
This is a matter of
national security.
We also need to make it
harder for people to buy
powerful assault weapons
like the ones that were used
in San Bernardino.
I know there are some
who reject
any gun safety measures.
But the fact is that
our intelligence and law
enforcement agencies -- no
matter how effective they
are -- cannot identify
every would-be mass shooter,
whether that individual is
motivated by ISIL or some
other hateful ideology.
What we can do -- and must
do -- is make it harder
for them to kill.
Next, we should put in place
stronger screening for those
who come to America without
a visa so that we can take a
hard look at whether they've
traveled to warzones.
And we're working with
members of both parties in
Congress to do exactly that.
Finally, if Congress
believes, as I do,
that we are at
war with ISIL,
it should go ahead and vote
to authorize the continued
use of military force
against these terrorists.
For over a year, I have
ordered our military to take
thousands of airstrikes
against ISIL targets.
I think it's time for
Congress to vote to
demonstrate that the
American people are united,
and committed,
to this fight.
My fellow Americans, these
are the steps that we can
take together to defeat
the terrorist threat.
Let me now say a word about
what we should not do.
We should not be drawn once
more into a long and costly
ground war in Iraq or Syria.
That's what groups
like ISIL want.
They know they can't defeat
us on the battlefield.
ISIL fighters were part of
the insurgency that we faced
in Iraq.
But they also know that if
we occupy foreign lands,
they can maintain
insurgencies for years,
killing thousands
of our troops,
draining our resources, and
using our presence to draw
new recruits.
The strategy that we are
using now -- airstrikes,
Special Forces, and working
with local forces who are
fighting to regain control
of their own country -- that
is how we'll achieve a
more sustainable victory.
And it won't require us
sending a new generation of
Americans overseas to fight
and die for another decade
on foreign soil.
Here's what else
we cannot do.
We cannot turn against one
another by letting this
fight be defined as a war
between America and Islam.
That, too, is what
groups like ISIL want.
ISIL does not
speak for Islam.
They are thugs and killers,
part of a cult of death,
and they account for a tiny
fraction of more than a
billion Muslims around the
world -- including millions
of patriotic Muslim
Americans who reject
their hateful ideology.
Moreover, the vast majority
of terrorist victims around
the world are Muslim.
If we're to succeed in
defeating terrorism we must
enlist Muslim communities
as some of our strongest
allies, rather than push
them away through suspicion
and hate.
That does not mean denying
the fact that an extremist
ideology has spread within
some Muslim communities.
This is a real problem
that Muslims must confront,
without excuse.
Muslim leaders here and
around the globe have to
continue working with us to
decisively and unequivocally
reject the hateful ideology
that groups like ISIL and al
Qaeda promote; to speak out
against not just acts of
violence, but also those
interpretations of Islam
that are incompatible with
the values of religious
tolerance, mutual respect,
and human dignity.
But just as it is the
responsibility of Muslims
around the world to root out
misguided ideas that lead to
radicalization, it is
the responsibility of all
Americans -- of every faith
-- to reject discrimination.
It is our responsibility to
reject religious tests on
who we admit into
this country.
It's our responsibility to
reject proposals that Muslim
Americans should somehow
be treated differently.
Because when we travel
down that road, we lose.
That kind of divisiveness,
that betrayal of our values
plays into the hands
of groups like ISIL.
Muslim Americans are our
friends and our neighbors,
our co-workers, our
sports heroes -- and, yes,
they are our men and women
in uniform who are willing
to die in defense
of our country.
We have to remember that.
My fellow Americans, I am
confident we will succeed in
this mission because we
are on the right side
of history.
We were founded upon a
belief in human dignity --
that no matter who you are,
or where you come from,
or what you look like, or
what religion you practice,
you are equal in the eyes of
God and equal in the eyes
of the law.
Even in this
political season,
even as we properly debate
what steps I and future
Presidents must take to
keep our country safe,
let's make sure we never
forget
what makes us exceptional.
Let's not forget that
freedom is more powerful
than fear; that we have
always met challenges --
whether war or depression,
natural disasters or
terrorist attacks -- by
coming together around our
common ideals as one
nation, as one people.
So long as we stay
true to that tradition,
I have no doubt
America will prevail.
Thank you.
God bless you,
and may God bless the United States of America.