joining us now republican presidential
candidate Donald Trump Donald how are
you this morning good morning but you
have to get the facts correct also
because in Sarasota is at five thousand
people and you can check this very
carefully because it was announced by
the Government 2,000 people not fighting
style than 12,000 12,000 people it was
announced by the convention center and
by government not by me and it was
twelve thousand so I want to get our
facts straight making yeah I don't we
have a lot to get through we got a lot
of people want to get through things
let's start with willie Geist a a a
jersey wrap dress made of networks is
keeping up with you not get your facts
right now
thousand-odd 5,000 willie yeah we can't
afford to have you asked a question at
this point make it down let me ask you
first
John McCain we just had him on a little
earlier yesterday he was asked about
some of your rhetoric some of the things
you said about Muslim Americans
including the question of the time
celebrating in Jersey City and he said
this has the effect of turning Muslims
all over the world against the United
States of America which is 99.4% people
who practice and honorable religion
other people have said that as well as
John McCain have a point I don't think
he has a point because I would say that
we are not exactly loved by many Muslims
and whether it's 10% like you said on
the show this morning or whether it's a
much larger percent you saw the soccer
game the other day with a we're giving
me a minute of silence I assume you saw
that where the stadium burst out talking
about and shouting out things that even
the soccer players were very embarrassed
nobody knew what to do if they were
doing Muslim chance and that was a week
ago or less than a week ago that was
right after the tragedy in paris they
were honoring within a minute of silence
and it was not a pretty picture so I
think John McCain is incorrect I think
we have to be strong I think we have to
be vigilant that many Muslim friends are
wonderful people but we nevertheless we
have to be extremely vigilant and
extremely strong and we have to
understand what the problem is I don't
think John McCain probably does
understand the problem
we're talking about a match the soccer
match in in turkey there are well over a
billion Muslims we don't paint entire
religion based on the the chance of a
few people in a sign of you get a lot of
people a lot of people that soccer game
we're going wild with their chanting and
everybody was very embarrassed we're not
talking about a few people gym what's
the purpose of all of this Aug you were
talking about people have to know the
problem is the fact you said the people
went wild after 911 muslims what wild
all over the world after 911 did you can
look at whether it's even a Ron R you
look at just about every muslim
government in the world
palestinians they they were holding
candlelight vigils holding prayer
services everybody but there are large
percentage of people that as you said
went wild and were celebrating all over
the world and I i order you don't
recognize it then we're never going to
solve the problem but there were a large
number of people that celebrated the
downing of the world
it keeps getting brought up I mean I'm
not bring it to you bring it is but it
keeps getting brought up but you know
you could go back to use to last weekend
the soccer game during that one minute
of silence in honor of the people that
were absolutely slaughtered disgustingly
slaughtered in that horrible thing that
took place in Paris and you see what
happened during that one better
as we as as we have so many issues to
talk about why is that important to you
why you bring that up and rallies why is
that right why should that be relevant
to voters who've been about night with
new hampshire well it is important
because you have to know the problems
but as far because we don't know the
process we have a president that won't
even mention deter more than Amy's if I
don't know what his problem is nobody
understands it he won't mention radical
Islamic terrorism he won't mention it he
you know it could be from a different
planet as far as he's concerned you're
not going to solve the problem unless
you're willing to talk about what the
problem is I'm willing to talk about
what the problem is that I do checked
out nice guy and you know he goes a
little bit wild on the show which you
know hopefully he did very well in the
ratings are sure he did actually but he
goes overboard while he brings it up you
bring it up this morning I didn't bring
it up you bring it up this morning but
we have to know what the problem is
before we could solve the problems and
these are people that don't even know
what the problem is and they don't want
to admit what the problem is because
it's not politically correct to admit
what the problem is Joe where you know
and I as I thought you make it that is a
fair point we are the ones that are
asking and chuck is the one that's what
it's come up in your speeches and I i
guess i would start by asking at this
week how would you characterize most
Muslim Americans how would you
characterize people are so many people
make it so many many friends within the
Muslim American community and within the
Muslim community community we have some
very radical people who want to do great
harm to you and to cure and to everybody
on your panel and to me and to this
country and the world now we can change
that doesn't exist and everybody will be
very happy or two
but it does exist wonderful people I
know so many of them and by the way the
1901 agree with me they say there is a
radical group of people that is doing
great harm and doing great harm to them
because they get tainted by what's going
on I think that sort of constant beating
of saying that this video of this
celebration exists when it's really in
question Donald is just it's gonna have
a negative impact on let's let's put it
to rest here's a story
number one take a look at the washington
post the other guy tried to pull back in
the store and by the way was the guy I
don't know why we need a supposedly he
interviewed me maybe even a couple of
times 35 years ago in the eighties
thirty-five years ago and then all of a
sudden you know I knew him I don't know
some reporters covering me yesterday I
see their name I see their byline I
don't even know what they look like that
supposedly he did you'd be in the
eighties I'm sure it's probably true I
mean it's possibly to but I've been
interviewed by thousands and thousands
of people were talking about 35 years
ago I don't know the guy but if you if
you don't address the problem and if you
don't know what the problem is you never
going to solve the problem
this world has a big problem and we have
a president that doesn't even want to
call it by its correct name and we have
to get with it very simple I would say
John hellman donald I would just say
that thats you can talk about that and I
think that's a potential about the level
of hatred within a certain community in
this case the Muslim community there's a
level of hatred that people don't want
to talk about
do you believe it is a small small
percent 10% 10% 10% but maybe 10% 72
percent is a lot to talk about the kind
of destruction they want to do the way
for those that work with us at the 6
o'clock hour there's a gallon poly thing
from 708 that said 7% 8% of Muslims
across the world thought the 911 attacks
were completely justified this question
a way that we like to ask it on that we
have our pollsters asked this question
and I asked you to use them as a better
as a potential hasbro's educated do you
think that Islam is inherently peaceful
religion that's been by some small
percentages you said whatever the
percentages perverted by some or do you
think that Islam is inherently violent
religion is something going on this
thing definitely going on I don't know
that that question can be answered could
be injured two ways it could be ensured
both ways but there's something going on
there there's something that is a lot of
hatred coming out of at least a big part
of it we see that we did you see whether
it's in Paris or whether it's the World
Trade Center or whether it's even a
soccer game out of respect for the
people that died in there was no respect
by a pretty good group of people in that
stadium and it was a week ago a week ago
something nasty coming out of there you
could answer it anyway you want but at
least we have to know the problem let's
get a rich get richer us though most
Americans would they not agree with
what Donald saying right now about even
if it's a small percentage it's a danger
and that's why I was saying the press
can fight Donald at the end of the day I
think it ends up helping him in
primaries yet I'm worried about the
ramifications of the conversation gets
too ugly and has I don't worry about it
and I don't help you I'll be honest I'm
not looking to do this for my whether I
win whether I lose about doing this or
that I'm doing it because somebody has
to bring it to the floor and nobody does
it and we have a leader's incompetent
and he doesn't do it but he doesn't want
to do it and he refuses to use the name
and it's almost like what you have to do
what has to be done to have him finally
the words he should be ordering to talk
about what the real problem is she won't
do it in a lot of people that are going
to support Donald Trump and other
republicans do wonder why he won't call
Islamic radicalism and extremism Islamic
radicalism or extremism why won't he do
that he can't speak for itself my senses
that he wants to keep the up position on
the religion she doesn't want to frame
it as a religious issue wants to keep
the focus on terrorists are radicals
whatever doesn't want to do a broader
problem that Islamic extremism
radicalism there is Islamic extremism
and I actually think what Donald Trump
said there is even a small percentage
could cause real mayhem as we saw in
Paris only a few people with the right
way can cause mayhem in an open
democratic society so even if we're
phenomenally successful in 99.9% of
people on the right tribal or even small
numbers can cause real damage
stitched up to 47 s fewer pressure right
now when you were over in Paris what is
it you would be trying to do on climate
change and what it is what is it you
would be trying to prevent if you were
leading the America United States at the
conference
well first of all one of the dumbest
statements have ever heard in politics
history of politics as I know it which
is pretty good
was Obama's statement that our number
one problem is global warming
when we have large groups of people
don't want to blow up every one of our
cities that want to destroy our country
that want to kill our people he's
worried about global warming I think
it's one of the dumbest things I've ever
seen or perhaps most naive he could be
naive in a certain way he actually
actually i think is somewhat naive if
you want to know the truth beyond
incompetent part I think his statement
the other day that we're going to show
them when we meet we mean business for
the future global warming and climate
change or whatever the new term is
because now they have extreme weather
you know that somebody new terms because
the old one still works very well you
know it used to be global warming and
then had a problem with it had some very
cool areas and that wasn't working so
you know they go climate change now it's
extreme weather so I don't know which
one of the many terms he used all
supposedly meaning the same thing for
him to say that that's more important
than shopping countries like by the way
north korea which is never even
mentioned you know they made one of the
worst deals in history when the media
randall but probably doesn't have to
clear weapons right now what about North
Korea nobody mentioned said that's like
when you have something to do don't want
to do you don't mention it because you
don't want to do it you don't want to
talk about it so sad and what's your
plan on climate change what would you be
saying it so that's what my take on
climate changes we wanted to have clean
air to breathe and we would have
beautiful clean water that's very
important to me
cleaning and environmental issues
something that our people don't know
this about me but many many projects all
over the world and I have received many
environmental awards you know the
environmentalists say two seasons awards
because it really does it but I receive
some of the house
awards and many of them for the work
I've done some of it I guess but you
know many of them and to be honest with
you you know I think it's very important
if you developing if you're building a
few factories remember this will
practically not allowed to use told him
or what do we do with our coalition
between China and they should be within
the arab chinese getting out there and
doing it well we have a planet and its a
certain size whether its arse putting it
into the year China when you get up to
its all the same thing so they're not
behaving at all never do and the way
they produced a good specialist
expensively cuz they don't have all the
rules regulations and having to do with
clean air and other things and many
other things by the way you look at what
happens with with charcoal we don't use
it
the industries in shatters but what does
get use is being shipped to China and
interviewing it into the year so you
know if you talking about global warming
or climate change
you have to make the world BAQ catches
behaving become non-competitive because
we're behaving other countries like
China and Vietnam and many others are
not behaving with the washington post is
with us thats question robert i Robert
good morning mr. Trump later today
you're going to be meeting with a group
of african-american pastors at Trump
Tower I would like to know what your
view is your message to them on two key
issues the black lives matter movement
in the unrest that race happened they
wanted to be that had meetings with the
before I have a great relationship I
have a great relationship with with many
of them and do want to me and I think it
was great and I was told it was in there
was fire whether it is or not that's
fine I think the meeting is a good thing
anyway
and there were quite a few days ago what
happened probably gets publicity
unfortunately is everything I do get
publicity and probably some of the black
lives matter folks grow them up sale you
shouldn't be meeting with dropped
because he believes it arrives better I
believe black lights to matter but I
believe our lives better
very strongly about like with the
character that's running running against
two people that I really believe it or
lose big league hillary and birdie and
he talked about like I was better than
he goes amigos it to a show in the
club's record black prizefighter black
last night he was he was a disgrace to
what I think happened is a lot of
pressure was put on it but I'm gonna
have a meeting I have no idea what the
meeting is really you know I'm going to
a meeting I have a great relationship
with the black pastors I've had I know
many of them will see what happens I
don't know if its endorsement I don't
know if it's a dude or swing by some I
think probably would be an endorsement
by some fantastic relationships with the
people but I do think that pressure was
put on them when they're there was a
beating by people that maybe disagree
with certain let's let's let's get some
other topics he really quickly
couple people that have moved up in the
polls and are now vying for second place
crews and the Rubio do you think Ted
Cruz is qualified to be President United
States with a good president yeah I do
think he's qualified I do think he would
be qualified to be absolutely what about
Marco Rubio I think so these are young
he's got a bad voting record in Florida
but he's got a week record on borders if
you look at broader security if you
don't get illegal immigration for a
weekend at its Ramon amnesty which
bothers me about it but he's a nice guy
I've gotten into him during the campaign
I like him and I think he would have a
shot so critical that were showing up
all right now that has you wanna be a
goal in the first place cruz second cars
and third Rubio fourth let me ask first
place every single state and every
single day
national polls do you think that is the
case I don't know I don't know group is
going to bypass the same more on
supposition that refines we need is just
showing joyfully say and jokingly say
dropped his picked up that point so we
talked about Marco Rubio supporting
amnesty you don't say bad things about
Ted Cruz but a lot of people in the
Intel community very concerned that Ted
Cruz is close to the RAM paul Vance a
traditional republican on issues of
Intel whether it's in assay data
collection you think Ted Cruz's too weak
on national security i didnt watching
this little debate between Rubio and
crews that I'd love to because I haven't
been so involved it's the one thing I
haven't been involved can you believe it
I'd love to watch it and they seem to be
attacking themselves are strongly
because somebody wants to be standing to
challenge because of the snow brought up
though do you think the NSA should have
the ability to collect all the data that
it was able to before
on the side of security sure you don't
get very interesting issue but I
happened to be and I i've been there
from the beginning I've been there from
before the paris attack you don't have
to have attacked everybody says exactly
this but I err on the side of security
on the side of security you know every
time I pick up the phone I assume people
are listening to my conversations I
don't like it but I have to make that
assumption I would really much on the
side of security
a lot of people would agree with me and
it just to go back to the beginning of
the Syrian button this do you think
there's any chance that video you think
you saw in Jersey City was the video of
people in the West Bank Palestinian
celebrating and I get to bring it up
again well it's so wonderful that you
brought it up again
just this is why you can't get away from
the subject of senate talking about
things that are what we did
15 minutes television fourteen years ago
sorta television it was written about
even though the reporter that says he
know me that I just don't know and he
may know me but I don't know him but
that's ok but the reporter wrote a
paragraph that he tried to pull back
from ok and the washington post ok
forget that I have received and as I
told you I have received of corals and
tweets from people find something to
find something but don't forget fourteen
fifteen years ago was it like it is
today we present but then you play video
fourteen fifteen years ago didn't even
put it in files a destroyer put the
stuff you know if you look back fourteen
fifteen years eighteen times in terms of
in terms of cinema and in terms of news
and everything else it would have to say
today you can press a button you can see
exactly what went on
you know two years ago when you go back
to 14 15 years that's like ancient
technology show we get all the newscasts
I mean we had twenty-four hour 300 now
this is not to cross is hundreds of
course I received many many tweets wheel
donald Trump 510 million people between
Facebook and Twitter received many
clicks when I was in Sarasota this
weekend three people probably of station
Mr Trump you're right about that we
lived in New Jersey we will comply we
watched it we watch people celebrating
in the streets
alright we will leave it there
air thank you very much for being on the
show this morning thank you very much
bigger hey youtube and I Luke Russert
thanks for checking out our MSNBC
channel subscribe by clicking right here
and click any empty videos over here to
watch the latest breaking news many
documentaries conversations from shipped
and other digital exclusives check it
out