The President: There's been
another mass shooting in
America -- this time, in a
community college in Oregon.
That means there are more
American families -- moms,
dads, children -- whose
lives have been changed forever.
That means there's another
community stunned with
grief, and communities
across the country forced to
relieve their own anguish,
and parents across the
country who are scared
because they know it might
have been their families
or their children.
I've been to
Roseburg, Oregon.
There are really
good people there.
I want to thank all the
first responders whose
bravery likely saved
some lives today.
Federal law enforcement
has been on the scene in a
supporting role, and we've
offered to stay and help as
much as Roseburg needs,
for as long as they need.
In the coming days, we'll
learn about the victims --
young men and women who were
studying and learning and
working hard, their eyes set
on the future, their dreams
on what they could
make of their lives.
And America will wrap
everyone who's grieving with
our prayers and our love.
But as I said just a few
months ago, and I said a few
months before that, and I
said each time we see one of
these mass shootings, our
thoughts and prayers are
not enough.
It's not enough.
It does not capture the
heartache and grief and
anger that we should feel.
And it does nothing to
prevent this carnage from
being inflicted someplace
else in America -- next
week, or a couple
of months from now.
We don't yet know why this
individual did what he did.
And it's fair to say that
anybody who does this has a
sickness in their minds,
regardless of what they
think their
motivations may be.
But we are not the only
country on Earth that has
people with mental illnesses
or want to do harm to
other people.
We are the only advanced
country on Earth that sees
these kinds of mass
shootings every few months.
Earlier this year, I
answered a question in an
interview by saying, "The
United States of America is
the one advanced nation on
Earth in which we do not
have sufficient common-sense
gun-safety laws -- even in
the face of repeated
mass killings."
And later that day, there
was a mass shooting at a
movie theater in
Lafayette, Louisiana.
That day!
Somehow this has
become routine.
The reporting is routine.
My response here at this
podium ends up being routine.
The conversation in
the aftermath of it.
We've become numb to this.
We talked about this after
Columbine and Blacksburg,
after Tucson, after Newtown,
after Aurora,
after Charleston.
It cannot be this easy
for somebody who wants to
inflict harm on other people
to get his or her hands
on a gun.
And what's become routine,
of course, is the response
of those who oppose any
kind of common-sense
gun legislation.
Right now, I can imagine the
press releases being cranked
out: We need more
guns, they'll argue.
Fewer gun safety laws.
Does anybody really
believe that?
There are scores of
responsible gun owners in
this country --they
know that's not true.
We know because of the
polling that says the
majority of Americans
understand we should be
changing these laws --
including the majority of
responsible,
law-abiding gun owners.
There is a gun for roughly
every man, woman, and child
in America.
So how can you, with a
straight face, make the
argument that more guns
will make us safer?
We know that states with the
most gun laws tend to have
the fewest gun deaths.
So the notion that gun laws
don't work, or just will
make it harder for
law-abiding citizens and
criminals will still get
their guns is not borne out
by the evidence.
We know that other
countries, in response to
one mass shooting, have been
able to craft laws that
almost eliminate
mass shootings.
Friends of ours, allies
of ours -- Great Britain,
Australia,
countries like ours.
So we know there are
ways to prevent it.
And, of course, what's also
routine is that somebody,
somewhere will comment and
say, Obama politicized
this issue.
Well, this is something
we should politicize.
It is relevant to our common
life together, to the
body politic.
I would ask news
organizations -- because I
won't put these facts
forward -- have news
organizations tally up the
number of Americans who've
been killed through
terrorist attacks over the
last decade and the number
of Americans who've been
killed by gun violence, and
post those side-by-side on
your news reports.
This won't be information
coming from me; it will be
coming from you.
We spend over a trillion
dollars, and pass countless
laws, and devote entire
agencies to preventing
terrorist attacks on our
soil, and rightfully so.
And yet, we have a Congress
that explicitly blocks us
from even collecting data
on how we could potentially
reduce gun deaths.
How can that be?
This is a political choice
that we make to allow this
to happen every few
months in America.
We collectively are
answerable to those families
who lose their loved ones
because of our inaction.
When Americans are killed in
mine disasters, we work to
make mines safer.
When Americans are killed in
floods and hurricanes, we
make communities safer.
When roads are unsafe, we
fix them to reduce
auto fatalities.
We have seatbelt laws
because we know it saves lives.
So the notion that gun
violence is somehow
different, that our freedom
and our Constitution
prohibits any modest
regulation of how we use a
deadly weapon, when there
are law-abiding gun owners
all across the country who
could hunt and protect their
families and do everything
they do under such
regulations
doesn't make sense.
So, tonight, as those of us
who are lucky enough to hug
our kids a little closer are
thinking about the families
who aren't so fortunate, I'd
ask the American people to
think about how they can get
our government to change
these laws, and to save
lives, and to let young
people grow up.
And that will require a
change of politics on
this issue.
And it will require that
the American people,
individually, whether
you are a Democrat or a
Republican or an
independent, when you decide
to vote for somebody, are
making a determination as to
whether this cause of
continuing death for
innocent people should be
a relevant factor in
your decision.
If you think this is a
problem, then you should
expect your elected
officials to reflect
your views.
And I would particularly ask
America's gun owners -- who
are using those guns
properly, safely, to hunt,
for sport, for protecting
their families -- to think
about whether your views are
properly being represented
by the organization that
suggests it's speaking for you.
And each time this happens
I'm going to bring this up.
Each time this happens I am
going to say that we can
actually do something about
it, but we're going to have
to change our laws.
And this is not something
I can do by myself.
I've got to have a Congress
and I've got to have state
legislatures and governors
who are willing to work with
me on this.
I hope and pray that I don't
have to come out again
during my tenure as
President to offer my
condolences to families
in these circumstances.
But based on my experience
as President, I can't
guarantee that.
And that's terrible to say.
And it can change.
May God bless the memories
of those who were killed today.
May He bring comfort to
their families, and courage
to the injured as they
fight their way back.
And may He give us the
strength to come together
and find the
courage to change.
Thank you.